ADITYA JAYANT GUPTA

E-5132 SECTOR 11 RAJAJIPURAM, LUCKNOW, UP 226017

+91 (829) 902-8247 # ADITYAGUPTA4213@GMAIL.COM # LINKEDIN.COM/ADITYA-JAYANT-GUPTA

Summary

Passionate software engineering student with a special interest in advanced web development. Strong analytical, organizational, and communication skills. Proficient in an assortment of technologies involving JavaScript and Python, along with experience in UI/UX design.

Skills

- Javascript
- React/NextJS
- API development

- Python
- HTML/CSS
- Adobe Creative Suite

Experience

Internship Trainee - 02/2022 to 03/2022

Tevatron Technologies

- Training and Internship program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.
- Worked on understanding various AIML approaches
- Worked with various libraries including Pandas, Seaborn, Numpy, Matplotlib, and OpenCV
- Learnt about AIML processes including EDA, data cleaning, clustering, plot generation, and more
- Developed a project on "Wholesale Customer Classification using AIML Models"

Future Ready Talent Intern - 10/2021 to 03/2022 Microsoft

- Conceptualized a disease prognosis prediction web app
- Developed a machine learning model using SVM, Naive Bayes, and Random Forest classifiers for predictive analysis
- Built a Python Flask API to connect the model to a JavaScript web application using Azure App Service
- Deployed working solution to the Azure cloud using Docker containerization with Azure Container Registries.

Education

Bachelor of Technology: 8.74 CGPA Computer Science and Engineering – **2019 to 2023** Babu Banarasi Das Engineering College, Lucknow

Intermediate: 80.8% CBSE, PCM + CS - 2017 to 2019

Lucknow Public School

High School: 9.6 CGPA CBSE – **2015 to 2017**

St. Mary's Convent Sr. Sec. School

Projects

DISEASE PROGNOSIS, MICROSOFT

Web application using machine learning and computational analysis to predict the most likely disease given a set of symptoms. Built as part of Microsoft Future Ready Talent internship.

https://github.com/adityagupta4213/FRT-Disease-Prognosis

- Conceptualized a disease prognosis prediction web app
- Developed a machine learning model using SVM, Naive Bayes, and Random Forest classifiers for predictive analysis
- Built a Python Flask API to connect the model to a JavaScript web application using Azure App Service
- Deployed working solution to the Azure cloud using Docker containerization with Azure Container Registries.

XPENSE, BABU BANARASI DAS ENGINEERING COLLEGE

A cross-platform expense tracking mobile application made with React Native.

https://github.com/adityagupta4213/xpense

- Making modular UI components using React Virtual DOM and JSX
- Managing routing and navigation using ReactRouterNative and ReactNavigation
- Dynamic data handling using state management through the React State Hook API
- Static data parsing and handling using React Props
- Firebase and Firestore integration for user authentication and data storage

Courses

- Python Programming IIT Kanpur
- Containers & Kubernetes Essentials CC0201EN, IBM Cognitive Class
- SQL and Relational Databases 101 DB0101EN, IBM Cognitive Class
- Sass Workflow Lawrence Turton, Udemy

Achievements

- Virtual Experience Participant at JP Morgan Chase & Co.
 - Software Engineering experience program by JP Morgan Chase & Co., providing an opportunity to work on interfacing with real-world financial JavaScript APIs and React web applications.
- Innovative India Coding Championship Finalist
 - Secured an all-India rank of 849 at IICC Round 2
- Google Kickstart 2022
 - Secured a global rank of # 3044 at Google Kickstart 2022 Round B
- Google Code Jam 2022
 - Secured a global rank of #7046 at Google Code Jam 2022 Round 1
- 5-star for Problem Solving and Python @ Hackerrank
 - Secured 5-star badges for Problem Solving and Python at Hackerrank
- Google Code-in 2016 and Code-in 2017
 - Participated in Google Code-in 2016 and 2017, collaborating on open-source projects.